Guide to the Amber Arthun Warburton Papers, 1917-1976 and undated RL.01341
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Affiliated Schools for Workers Series, 1932-1935
  - Printed Material
    - Periodicals and Newsletters, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Fairfax County Series, 1938-1947
  This series contains correspondence, notes, reports, press releases, clippings, printed material, and photographs from Warburton's involvement in several school organizations in Fairfax County, Virginia, in the mid-1940's.The material is organized by type (correspondence, printed material, etc.) within alphabetically arranged subjects.
  - Child Consultation Service
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1945-1946 and undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Reports, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases and Clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Franklin Sherman School Health Program
    - Correspondence, Minutes, Press Releases, Notices, and Forms, 1943-1946 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Reports and Notes. Kellogg Foundation, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Reports and Notes. Kellogg Foundation, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Reports and Notes, 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1944-1946 and undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Franklin Sherman School Parent-Teachers' Association, 1942-1945 and undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Lay Health Association, 1945 and undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - McLean Community Forum, 1944-1945 and undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Northern Virginia District Parent-Teachers' Association Conference, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Parent-Teachers' Association Child Guidance Workshop, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Program for the Improvement of Instruction in Virginia Elementary Schools, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - School Health Program, 1945-1947 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - School Improvement Association, 1938-1946 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Social Survey, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Agriculture Series, 1942-1947
  This series has correspondence, notes, reports and drafts of reports, clippings, and printed material from Warburton's 1946 study of education for migrant children in the Cotton Belt. The study was part of a larger report on postwar agricultural and economic problems in the Cotton Belt. The report was prepared for the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Agriculture and formally presented to Congress in July, 1947. Besides the report, probably the most interesting material is the field reports on social and economic conditions in northwestern Arkansas in 1946.
  - Correspondence, 1946, Feb.-March (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1946, April-May and undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Drafts of Report, Education for Children in Migrant Families (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Additional Drafts and Final Report, Education for Children in Migrant Families of the Cotton Belt (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary Draft of Project VII, Southern Educational Problems (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Interviews, Notes, Reports, Family Schedules, and Printed Material from the Arkansas Study, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Reports from the Children's Bureau, 1946-1947 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Interviews and Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material, 1942-1946 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Printed Material, 1944-1946 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Printed Material and Clippings, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Volume: Study of Agricultural and Economic Problems in the Cotton Belt (July, 1947) (Box 23)